You Tube - Video Running Time 02 : 27 : 51
You Tube search name - Mahal
30 years back , on a stormy and rainy night ...
close to Allahabad , 2 miles away from the railway station ...
on the banks of Jamuna , there is a bungalow called Sangam Bhavan ...
which has been lying desolate and vacant for ages .
It is said that on the nights of torrential rainfall ...
a boat appears from somewhere , and stops near this bungalow ...
located on the banks of river Jamuna .
And then someone is heard crying in the bungalow .
People are scared of this place and consider it inauspicious .
But , in the quarters of this desolate bungalow ...
an old gardener still lives .
But a strange story narrated by this old gardener ...
is very famous about this mansion ...
that , a very painful love story had transpired here .
Yes sir , a very woeful love story took place here .
A 40-45 year old man ...
would come here through the sea road to build this mansion ...
and would return at the break of dawn .
When the mansion was ready , a beautiful woman came with him ...
and they began living here .
All day , she would anxiously await nightfall ...
and she would sit at the riverbank awaiting her beloved .
Be it a storm or hurricane , that man would come here at midnight !
He would then leave at the break of dawn .
One night , it was raining very heavily .
There was a storm on the river Jamuna .
The boat of love was rowing towards its destination ...
when it got caught in a whirlpool and sank .
But , while drowning , his last words were heard .
' Kamini , don 't get disheartened . '
' Don 't let our love fail with this blow of fate . '
' Our love has not failed , and never will . '
' I will come back again . '
With these assurances , Kamini began searching ...
for her peace and love in the waves of the river .
Finally , one night , she got caught ...
in the whirlpool and drowned herself .
And this beautiful mansion of their love became desolate !
After 40 years , you are the first man ...
who has come to live here again .
- That 's it ? - Yes , that 's it .
The story is over .
No , it 's not over .
It was left incomplete .
You didn 't tell me who that couple was ?
Who they were and where they came from ...
is not known . They died with that secret .
After their death , nobody came here asking for them .
How long have you been here ?
I have been here right from the beginning .
The garden in this mansion has been grown by me .
You bought this mansion . You should know their whereabouts .
No , I don 't know . I bought it at auction .
And on the documents , the owner 's name is blank .
That is why I could not find the original owners .
You may not know anything ...
but don 't you even know the owner 's name ?
The servants cannot know the name of their masters .
He never told me and I never asked .
Nobody mentioned his name .
That is why I never knew .
Anyway , don 't make this mistake again .
Just for information , you should know the name of your new employer .
You never know when the need may arise .
- My name is Hari Shankar . - What are you saying ?
The whole of Kanpur and Allahabad knows you .
You are the son of a famous judge .
May you flourish in this place .
You must be tired from the journey .
You please rest . Your bedroom is there .
Your bed has been laid out .
Are there any other orders for me , sir ?
There are , but nothing you can carry out on this stormy night .
You tell me sir . Don 't worry about inconveniencing me .
How far is this mansion from the city ?
Around four miles away .
- Then you will have to walk . - I will go , sir . You tell me .
- Do you know where Georgetown is ? - Which town , sir ?
Georgetown , where the bungalows of the barristers are located .
It 's close to the High Court .
I know the place . Where do I have to go there ?
Go to Barrister Shivnath 's place .
Tell him that his friend from Kanpur has come .
Alright sir , I will take your leave .
What mystery is this ? Who were you ?
Why do you look like me ?
So this is your second birth ?
The world is steeped in silence
The stars are silent in the sky
The world is at rest ...
yet my heart is restless
In the dark stillness ...
I am startled by footsteps nearing
The sound echoes , as though someone ...
were walking within the depths of my soul
Or is it the sound of my heart ...
quickening with hope ?
The one meant to return will return
How is it that moths are dying , but with no flame to burn them ?
How can one feel the pain of an arrow , though there is no archer ?
How long should one endure such unending despair ?
The stirring in my heart tells me ...
the one meant to return will return
This beauty is desolate and wandering , searching for her destination
Like a boat without a boatman , searching for the shore
How much longer must I wait to reach the shore ?
The stirring in my heart tells me ...
the one meant to return will return
Who is it ?
What 's the matter ?
What 's the matter , Shankar ? What happened ?
Wait , let me get my senses back .
I want to be silent for some time .
Why is my portrait here ?
Shivnath , did I build this mansion in my last birth ?
And to complete my unfulfilled love story , I have come here ?
This is just a coincidence .
If it 's a coincidence then it 's a very dangerous one .
And if that is a coincidence then what did I see ?
Why did I see that ghost ?
The environment of this place has influenced you .
It was nothing but a hallucination .
No , I am not a hallucination , I am a reality .
I am not a hallucination , I am a reality !
Indeed , this place is very dangerous and inauspicious .
No wonder your father is repenting buying this place .
You made a very big mistake by coming here alone at night .
I came here alone because , the story which is famous ...
about this place , I wanted to experience it myself .
I didn 't know this story would be connected with my last birth .
No , this is not right .
Come with me . You should not fall for this so soon .
You are an educated man .
Use your intelligence .
It would be better if you go back to Kanpur .
You did a very wise thing by agreeing to go back to Kanpur .
Here , in Allahabad , you wouldn 't forget that unlucky mansion !
And then there would be more problems .
You are aware that your father has ordered me several times ...
that , the unlucky property he has bought by mistake ...
I should sell it or auction it as soon as possible .
And even you going against your father 's wishes ...
is a very big mistake .
You are right .
Therefore , you should stay away from such things .
Because , only your fiancee has a right over your life and thoughts .
You belong to her .
Right , but don 't sell that mansion .
Tell father that it cannot be sold .
I may get a shock if it is sold , and I may not bear it .
Okay , I am going now .
Listen , a few of my things remain there .
- Can you please collect them ? - Okay , I will go there .
The one meant to return will return
How is it that moths are dying but with no flame to burn them ?
How can one feel the pain of an arrow though there is no archer ?
How long should one endure ...
You are back ?
I was sure that you would come back .
Why do you look so surprised ?
I am not your imagination .
I am not a dream .
Look at me closely .
Don 't touch me .
Just look at me . Talk to me .
Who are you ?
In spite of explaining to you , you have come back here ?
I didn 't come , I was called back .
You have been very unjust to me .
I was having a beautiful dream ...
and you startled me .
No , you were intoxicated by that poison ...
which you consumed thinking it was a cold drink . Let 's go .
Slow poison often tastes sweet .
And deceit is always beautiful !
And an intelligent man should know this .
The one meant to return will return
Wait ! Have you lost your senses completely ?
Don 't you understand your death is playing tricks on you ?
Perhaps you are right .
I am feeling very helpless .
Wrong . A human being has a heart and a mind too .
Even when an animal is about to be trapped in a snare ...
he tries to save himself .
And you , being a human being don 't get shocked ?
Sir , there is no room for argument in this case of love .
You will never win . Come here .
Come to me .
Sir ...
it 's almost morning , I am leaving ...
but , I want to tell you that ...
don 't try to come between him and me ...
or you shall regret it .
- What happened ? - Nothing !
- Who is it ? - I am the gardener , sir .
What happened sir ? What was this explosion ?
Come inside .
- Yes , sir ? - The story you told me about this mansion ...
you forgot to tell me the most important part of the story .
- Which part ? - The lady who was that man 's lover ...
her spirit roams around in this mansion .
- No , sir . - But , we have seen her many times .
Perhaps you have hallucinated .
I have been here for the past 40 years .
I would have surely have seen her at least once .
It 's strange . Okay , you may go .
Shall I send tea for you ?
I 'm asking you for the last time ...
Your tea , master .
Put it here . Go .
I am asking for the last time , won 't you leave this evil house ?
- No . - So you have made up your mind to die here ?
If this is my fate then I have no objection to it .
Then I will have to sell this mansion .
Never ! You cannot sell it !
We will see about it later .
I have come to meet you both because I need your help .
I am surprised seeing you here .
You never pass this way . Tell me , what brought you here ?
My very close friend has fallen in the snare of a woman ...
who is deceiving him in the form of a spirit .
The matter is getting very critical ...
that very soon , either he will go insane ...
or will die .
- So ? - I want to divert his attention from her ...
so that we get enough time to get him married .
You both are famous for helping men who have strayed .
That is why I have come to you .
But , we are poison and you want to use us as medicine ?
Shouldn 't it be the reverse ?
I know it but , some deadly diseases ...
are cured with poison .
When there 's pain , a morphine injection is administered before medicine .
Okay , you tell me the rates .
Get the patient . Money will be decided on seeing the sickness .
I will get him here under some pretext .
But he shouldn 't think anything else after he comes here .
Be careful that the snare you make should not be weak and loose .
Let him come here .
He will come .
He has arrived .
Have him wait until midnight and see to it that he doesn 't leave .
I am sorry but , you will have to wait .
- How long ? - For some time .
Alright , I will wait .
But , do inform her that I am anxious to meet her .
I will convey your message .
Thank you .
Will I have to wait more ?
- Are you bored ? - No , but ...
Then wait for some more time .
But for how long ? I hope it 's not for ages .
I could be for ages , but for you the wait is just for a few hours .
The wait differs from person to person .
Please come , sir .
Please come .
Please sit .
I am sorry that you had to wait for so long .
You look quite disturbed .
I received your notice this evening .
I have come here to discuss it .
Tell me .
This notice says that the mansion called Sangam Bhavan ...
has been bought by you .
Therefore , I 'll have to vacate that place as soon as possible .
But , I cannot leave it .
That is why , I have come here with a request ...
that , have mercy on me and sell it back to me .
I will pay whatever price you ask .
And all my life , I will be indebted by your favor .
Please tell me .
If you would earnestly ask us , we would not refuse you .
I am glad that you didn 't ask for our heart .
We will return that mansion to you .
But , on one condition .
- What ? - We 've heard that you are a very good artist .
- Tell me . - Make a portrait of us sisters in a way that ...
it feels the magic is one , but the chants are two .
I did not understand .
You didn 't ? One arrow and two bows .
One view , two eyes .
I have yet not understood the meaning .
Okay wait , let me explain .
Chandni , play the music .
Listen to me , my dear
Where is love in the music ?
Look into my eyes and listen to me
This night will not come again
The youth will pass by
This night is enveloped in mirth
It makes the hearts fonder and closer
If it passes away like this ...
you will regret it all your life
Even if you wait for it anxiously ...
this night will never come again
My youth is dancing to the music of my heartbeat
Take my hand and lead me wherever you want
Why are you worried when I belong to you now ?
I swear by you , this night will never come again
The one meant to return will return
I got your prey right up to you ...
and you couldn 't even ensnare him ?
You have ruined everything .
Once the bird is out of the cage , he flies even higher !
Anyway , I will think of some other way .
Are you very restless for me ?
Yes !
Do you know the consequences of your restlessness ?
My death !
- Have you decided ? - Look at me closely .
Do you need an answer ?
Come , if you are ready to die .
- Where does this path lead ? - Don 't you remember ?
You don 't remember anything !
A human being forgets his last birth .
That is why , even you have forgotten ...
that you were my lover in the last birth .
This secret passageway leads to the center of the mansion .
You used to come to meet me through this way .
But I am not dead . That is why I remember the past so well .
You loved me with the utmost passion .
You hid me here in this mansion , away from the eyes of the world .
I anxiously passed the hours of the day to see you at night .
You would come to meet me every night , at any cost .
One night , on your way here , you were enveloped by the river .
And I died a torturous death thinking about you .
I remember it vividly .
You took another birth and were free from the woes of last birth .
But I have been wandering around , looking for you ...
sometimes in the valley of death and sometimes on the road of life .
And then you came and I recognized you .
You may not remember me , but my love nestles in your heart .
And that has pulled you here .
My love has compelled you to die for me ...
because this is the only way we both can unite .
If you die , your physical being which is a barrier between us ...
will fall and our souls will unite .
Come . To unite with me , you will have to jump in that river .
Alright .
But , wait a minute .
I am afraid . What if again ...
you disappear into the darkness of death ?
- Then ? - I can come back to life .
- How ? - Come , let me explain .
If my spirit enters the body of any such woman ...
whom you like and can kill ...
In that case , it is impossible to get you alive .
You don 't have to find such a woman . I 'll tell you about her .
A beautiful woman lives here , with a veil covering her face ...
and she serves you every day .
- Who is she ? - The gardener 's daughter .
- The gardener 's daughter ? - Yes .
If you lift her veil , you may perhaps like her .
Then we may find a way to our union .
- Alright . - But , before I come in the form of that woman ...
I want to be sure that you won 't change seeing me in her body .
Forget her . I am willing to accept you even as a serpent .
- Then when should I come ? - Right now .
I will vacate that body for you right away .
No , don 't be in such a hurry .
- Then when ? - When she gets tea for you in the morning .
You look at her closely ...
and then decide .
Now you go ...
and wait for the beautiful morning of our union .
Open the door .
Master ? What happened ?
Yes , master ?
Get the tea early in the morning .
Alright , sir .
- What is the matter , sir ? - Nothing .
- Send the tea early . - Shall I send it at 8 A.M. ?
No , at 6 A.M.
Asha , wake up .
No , I won 't go !
Is he dead ?
No , he is alive .
Then bring him along .
Wait !
Shiv , you go inside .
You did not listen to me ?
Come with me !
Sit down .
Do you want to die running after a shadow ?
Do you want to commit an injustice to your fiancee without reason ?
Look at me !
You want to kill living beings and bring the dead alive ?
Do you really want that ?
You can go if you want ...
but , only by moving me from your path !
And it won 't be easy to move me and walk towards your doom !
Do you understand ? And yet , if you insist on going ...
then take this !
Come on , take it !
Now move me from your path .
I asked Shiv to go because ...
whatever would transpire between you and me ...
there should be no witness to it .
I have written a suicide note that I am responsible .
Pick up the gun . What are you seeing ?
Shoot me , I am quite tough .
And your aim is also not that bad .
Pick up the gun !
Shoot me !
What did you gain by doing this ?
That picture signified , even I was happy once upon a time .
I have ruined that today .
My joys have been killed .
I have yielded to my friends and well wishers advice .
You have done right thing . You will know later ...
how happy and peaceful you are .
Pain can be inflicted with the incision of an operation ...
which is performed to cure a person .
One day , you will forget all the pain inflicted upon you .
Yes , I will forget everything .
I will stifle my feelings .
I will forget her .
It is difficult .
It is very difficult to forget love
It is not easy to quench the fire of love
This is not a game . It is a matter of feelings
It makes people laugh and cry at the same time
There are no restrictions in the life of lovers
You are ecstatic at the victory and bless at the loss
I am in a dilemma but I cannot forget you
Because , it is not possible to forget you
A bride hidden by her veil looks very pretty !
Like the dice in the palm , who can make you win when it 's revealed ?
Tell me , what are you going to win ?
For whom will you play , for me or against me ?
At this moment you are my fate ...
and my heart is beating to catch a glimpse of you .
Are you beautiful ?
Aren 't you beautiful ?
Your hands are beautiful , and fair , too .
They 're also shapely and fragile .
Now I would like to lift your veil and look at my future .
Are you feeling shy ? Of me ?
Oh ! You are feeling shy of the light ? Alright .
Now lift up your veil ...
and let me see how bright my future shines !
Let me see the glow of your face .
The one meant to return will return
Thank you . I am glad you reminded me that ...
I too am caged , just like you .
I am helpless .
What happened , Ranjana ?
Sister-in-law , I was humiliated .
He was about to lift my veil ...
and left it as if he stopped himself from committing a sin .
He went away outside leaving me stunned and baffled .
Didn 't he come back ?
It would have been better if he hadn 't come back .
Then my fate would have been decided at that time .
But , he came back after some time ...
and said that he would take me far away ...
and there , he would love me .
But I didn 't understand the meaning of his words .
I fear that every night , at the strike of 2 A.M ...
some clock will carry her message ...
that I should not forget her .
I got her message last night too and I became restless .
That is why I want to go to some desolate place ...
where I cannot hear her .
Then maybe I can begin to treat my poor wife fairly ...
whose love has to survive amidst the storm in my life .
- Whose letter is it ? - Your sister 's .
' Sister-in-law , it 's been two years but ...
the veil of the nuptial night still covers my face ...
and I feel that this veil will never be removed . '
' I have have resolved that ...
until he uncovers my veil ...
I will not show him my face . '
' I still have not learned what kind of a man he is ...
but he is cast over my life like a deadly , deep secret ...
and I fear him . ' ' Since the time we left home ...
I want you to know what I have been going through . '
I cannot walk anymore .
Be bold Ranjana . We still have much farther to go .
- I am very tired . - Alright , rest for awhile .
No sir , it is very dangerous to stay here in the night .
On that hillock is a famous rest house .
By nightfall , we will reach there .
Let 's go .
Be alert .
- What happened ? - What is down there ?
It looks like a sea of fire .
It 's not a sea of fire . The tribe of this area ...
is taking a woman who has sinned ...
to the temple of their deity , so that she can be put on trial .
On trial ?
To see if her husband 's accusation of infidelity is true .
How will they know it ?
She will dance in front of the deity ...
and in the middle of the dance , the priest will aim ...
four knives one by one , on her .
If she is not pierced by a single knife ...
then she will be considered innocent .
It 's a strange custom . Can we go there ?
- Of course . - No , we will not go there .
Why not ? If she doesn 't die , she will be proven innocent !
Men are very suspicious .
Come with me .
' Do you realize what a deadly experience that was ? '
' I don 't know how many more such incidents I 've gone through . '
' If the paths are so dangerous , how tough the journey must be . '
' Falling at every step and apprehensive about my future ...
I wished that I could die '
Leading a life of fear ...
it would be better if I die
There is nothing left to look forward to in life
It would be better if I die
Let him also see how my heart has broken in this grief
The tears in my eyes ...
let them well up
What I have endured ...
let it pass once and for all
Let him see how he has tormented me
It would be nice if he knows that
Don 't worry , I will not torment you anymore .
I empathize with you . Don 't form a wrong opinion of me .
' Come with me . '
' What can I do ? I am forming wrong opinions . '
' How would a few words help ?
' Even if I believe these words , then what I am going through ...
should I consider that as a dream ? '
' And even if it is a dream , then it is a nightmare . '
' It is very scary '
This is the rest house but , it 's not very old .
This place is very peaceful .
Will we stay here forever ?
Yes , this is the peace I was looking for .
In this solitude , I can live peacefully .
Then , I can fall in love with you .
Quiet !
My heart is remembering you again . Oh disloyal lover , please come back
Again my heart experiences a piercing pain . Again my heart is murdered
I had a dream which was left unfulfilled
I have no complaints against the world or of my fate
The false promises of your love ruined my life
Something has burned as I feel a fire from my heart
I fear that this fire may not destroy the intoxication of love
You who are annoyed with me , please don 't ridicule this love
Sir ...
Madam ?
Who is crying ?
Madam ? What happened ? Where is the master ?
- He 's been out since yesterday . - Yesterday ?
- Where has he gone ? - I don 't know .
You don 't know ? ! That 's dangerous , very dangerous !
- How is he related to you ? - Who ?
- The master . - He is my husband .
Husband ? No .
A husband doesn 't behave like this .
Then how is he supposed to be ?
However he may be but , surely not like you !
- You are right . - You left madam alone and went away ?
She was crying . It 's very bad !
I am ashamed of my behavior .
But what is the cause of your behavior ?
I plead to you , tell me everything !
I feel stifled in this solitude .
I am fed up . If you don 't like me then I can live with it .
I will depart from your life .
But please tell me the reason . I promise , I will go away .
Don 't punish me like this by slowly torturing me to death .
The one meant to return will return
' So , that 's it , the amount of humiliation a woman can endure . '
' I have endured . Now I cannot bear it anymore . '
' I will find out the secret at any cost ...
that which is the barrier between him and me ...
and against which I have dashed myself and tried to remove it . '
I am sitting at the peak of a volcanic mountain ...
and I want to lose myself in this grief ...
so that , whatever is going to happen tomorrow ...
will happen today . That 's all I want ! '
No Ranjana , don 't do that !
She cannot do it . We will go there and talk to her .
She has gone crazy . If she lives like this , she will die soon !
Once again , the smile stopped itself from coming on my lips
I am the lamp which could never give out light
I am the one whose desires were never fulfilled
The joys have vanished and sorrows have victimized me
I am the bride who could never adorn
I am the bride who never glowed with love
There 's no point in trying to douse the fire within me
Why should I prove the betrayer is my beloved ?
This is my life now
The lonely night is passing by ...
but my helpless heart has no one around
I am awaiting my death
My foe , I have recognized you .
Today I will surely find out the mystery behind all this .
When he starts coming closer to me , you stop him .
You convey some message to him .
Father , the clock has stopped !
What is it ? Oh ! The clock stopped ?
- How did it happen ? - It 's stopped , look there !
It never has stopped , this is not a good omen !
There is a storm in my mind . How can you sleep so peacefully ?
' Traitor , fearing you ...
I am jumping into the deep ravine ...
from where , you will not even get my dead body . '
Oh , who shot the arrow ...
straight into my heart ?
Oh my fragile heart
I was injured so badly ...
that my heart was shattered
Oh tears , flow out . Tell me , how should I live ?
There was a fire of love within me , and my heart was engulfed
If love was to be devastated ...
the aim was perfect
I tried hard , but I could not save my heart
When I made an appeal ...
did anyone hear me out ?
Who has destroyed me ?
My heart said my eyes and my eyes said my heart
I 've come back , Kamini .
You 're back ? Where 'd you go ?
I was caught up in a helpless situation .
But , I was very worried about you .
- I was restless for you . - I believe you .
Your words and your sighs ...
prove that you were very restless for me .
I have no complains against you .
What have you decided this time ?
I want to know .
This time I have come to die ...
or , to get you .
Then come and get me .
The gardener 's daughter is alive . Go kill her .
I am within you and I am confident that you want me .
The girl will come to you in the morning .
You will stick to your decision ...
and get me .
Good bye , sister-in-law .
- I want to give a statement . - Alright .
Constable , take down her statement .
- Your name ? - Ranjana .
Ms. Ranjana Devi . Your address ?
Okay , tell me more ?
He is my husband . He has been very cruel to me .
He has been unfaithful to me .
And today , for another woman , he has poisoned me .
- What ? - You 've been poisoned ?
Abdul , get the doctor quickly !
I will not live long now .
Put a thumb print .
- Tea , master . - Put it down .
Are you very beautiful ?
- Why do you ask ? - I want to see you .
Lift your veil .
- Who is it ? - Police . - What do you want ?
- You are under arrest . - Why ?
- You committed this murder ? - No .
Yes , you have ! You hated your wife !
And because of this hatred , you poisoned her !
- No ! - You surely despised your wife .
You had never seen her face .
- Did you ever see her ? - Yes .
If you have , then identify her amongst these pictures !
Tell me who the woman is who has spent so many months with you !
Is she your wife ?
None of them is your wife !
You surely cannot identify her .
You yourself said that you have never seen your wife .
You hated her and meted out atrocities on her .
These are the letters written by her . You killed her ...
and the proof is this testimony of your wife ...
which is in the police register along with her signature .
Ashabala , daughter of Krishna , please be present .
She is the vile woman , that sorceress ...
because of whom , this cruel man ...
poisoned his innocent and feeble wife !
She is the vicious woman who instigated him ...
to commit this heinous offense !
I object to this accusation !
The story of the accused with this woman ...
on which the public prosecutor is stressing , is fabricated !
And to prove my claim , I present this evidence !
This beautiful and alluring face ...
is of the woman who was killed for her sake !
I would like to question the esteemed jury .
Can you believe that an illiterate gardener 's daughter ...
this shabbily dressed woman ...
could be the reason for a beautiful woman 's murder ?
This ugly woman ...
My real name is Asha .
I am the daughter of Krishna , the gardener .
The statement which I am about to give ...
every word of it is worth pondering .
That is why I request ...
everyone to please listen to my testimony carefully .
The love story which is famously connected with that mansion ...
I , too , had heard that story from my father at various times .
When I grew up , a desire arose in my heart too ...
that I should also be loved in the same manner .
But who could love a gardener 's daughter with so much passion ?
I could understand this truth .
That is why I thought of a new plan ...
to fulfill my desire .
I would stealthily enter the house at midnight ...
and pretend to be the woman who was loved in that palace .
I would pretend to love the man who built that house !
Gradually , I became obsessed with the idea that I am the woman .
I fell in love with the picture of the man who built the house .
And then one night , when I entered the mansion ...
I saw .
At first I was scared and hid .
But when I saw his face clearly , I was stunned !
He looked exactly like the man in the picture .
He was the one for whom I waited so long .
He was born again and had come to the same mansion .
I was hiding and watching him .
He saw his own picture .
He knew about me and started thinking I was his Kamini .
I took advantage of the situation and decided ...
that I would trap him in my love ...
and convince him that I was Kamini 's spirit .
I took him along the secret ways of the mansion .
I feared that before my love progressed , if he would learn ...
who I was , then my beautiful dream would get shattered .
And when I was sure ...
that even if he would learn I was the gardener 's daughter ...
he would not hate me .
I decided to reveal my true self to him .
I told him that ...
I could be alive . If he would like to see me in her body ...
then he should kill her so that I could enter her body .
What I meant was that when he opened that girl 's veil ...
he would recognize me .
I intentionally played this dangerous game .
I could have even lost my life .
But , I was in love with him .
I was even ready to die .
But unfortunately ...
I neither died , nor did I get him .
And my beautiful dream was shattered .
Your honor , the members of the jury , the accused is innocent .
He is not guilty .
I start my defense with these words .
The claim that for his own debased reasons ...
the accused murdered his wife ...
is an allegation . There is no evidence to prove it !
Making false accusations in a serious case of homicide ...
and fabricating stories is like committing one more murder !
Loving someone and not being able to forget that person ...
is it written in any book of law that it is a crime ?
The accused tried his best to forget his love .
But the so-called innocent girl raked his wounds which wanted to heal ...
and provoked the fire which he wanted to douse !
Even she committed a sin which is proven by these letters .
She tortured herself to death !
If you want to punish an innocent man ...
for the crime of this woman ...
a man who is helpless himself ...
then forget about the law and order that prevails !
Members of the jury , look here .
Look into these barren eyes ...
which carry the image of a ruined life .
Tell me , can you find a trace of blood in them ?
Tell me , can you see a spark in them ...
which can be seen in the eyes of a murderer ?
People who can differentiate between good and bad ...
you know that ...
I have no written answer to these claims .
Therefore , please don 't decide on the basis of these letters .
Don 't forget that !
Jury , before you decide the fate of the accused ...
try to judge and understand whether or not ...
this murder is just an allegation or was it really committed by him ?
Remember my words that ...
the accused is innocent .
He is innocent !
But the court and the jury think ...
that the accused is guilty .
Therefore , with deep regret ...
we announce a capital punishment for the accused .
I have called you here to tell you that ...
I am going to die tomorrow .
But don 't become disheartened and feel sad .
We shall meet again .
- Where ? - In this world !
I will come back .
I will be born again .
I have been born several times in search of my love .
I will endure one more death .
I will be born again !
My love , my thirst , the love for me in your eyes ...
will pull me back here .
But you don 't die for me .
Because if you die , then in the barren land of death ...
we will unite , but I don 't want to belong to you there .
I want to get you here , where I have always loved you ...
I have been unsuccessful and have gone back .
I am going to be hanged ...
and I want to get you in this world .
That is why I want a sacrifice from you .
I want you to be snatched away from me in this birth ...
so that you are born again for my sake .
I know it 's a very big sacrifice .
But Kamini , if you want that we should meet again ...
then you will have to pass this trial .
Tell me , what have you decided ?
For you , and to get you ...
I will pass any trial .
You are very precious to me and I want you .
The sacrifice for which you have asked ...
is far more difficult than dying a thousand deaths .
And for a woman , it is all the more difficult .
But , if I can get you back at this cost ...
then the cost won 't be too great for me .
I am ready .
- You heard our conversation ? - Yes , I heard .
I want a final favor from you in return of our friendship .
Before I die , snatch away my Kamini from me .
You get married to her ...
so that I feel the pain of this separation in this very birth .
And I don 't have to endure any other pains in the next birth .
What are you saying ?
Don 't argue with me . I don 't have much time .
Answer me , yes or no ?
Shivnath , you have tried everything to save me .
Make one more last attempt .
Do it today so that tomorrow , I can see from the gallows ...
that you snatched away my Kamini from me in my interest .
And to get her in the next birth ...
I have intimated my fate .
Look at me for some time ...
I want to look at you to my heart 's content .
We have received a letter and the contents are very dangerous .
- What is it ? - A woman has written that ...
she is committing suicide and ...
she holds her husband responsible for it .
- Where is the letter from ? - The address says Kanpur .
But it was sent from Allahabad .
The address of the sender is not known .
We are trying to locate her husband .
- What is the name of the sender ? - Ranjana .
' Sister in law , after great difficulty ...
I have learned his secret . '
' I know he is not mine and can never belong to me . '
' But I did not give up ...
if I cannot get him here , I will get him in another world ...
and to get him , I am going towards my death . '
' And I am dying , accusing him of poisoning me ...
so that he receives the death sentence for killing me ...
and comes to me . '
This letter proves that she committed suicide .
And this is the police report regarding her signatures .
Now you have look at them closely and decide ...
if false evidence is taking an innocent man to the gallows ?
These are the orders from the chief justice .
Who is it ?
I tried to run a lot ...
but I 'm glad my fate injured me again .
Indeed , after this sacrifice ...
there 'll be nothing left to achieve .
I 'm sorry my last favor proved to be so expensive for you .
My friendship has caused you a great loss .
But , I shall make up for all the losses .
Don 't be disheartened . I have a solution for your problem .
Look at me . Don 't feel so sad .
A human being shouldn 't feel so sad .
You were in such a great hurry !
No man could have endured so much !
You were in such great haste .
And I was late in my sacrifice .
But , you will come back again .
This beauty is desolate and wandering , searching for her destination
Like a boat without a boatman , searching for the shore
How much longer must I wait to reach the shore ?
The stirring in my heart tells me ...
the one meant to return will return